<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-yellowstone</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	      <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-yellowstone/selected-articles</id>
	      <rel>1</rel>
	      <text>A Great National Park. Hon. N. P. Langford, of Slontann, the leader of the famous Yellowstone expedition of last year, is now in Washington, and, in eonneetion with Professor Hayden, who had charge of the government expedition of this year, is engaged in promoting the project of declaring all that district, including the canon of the Yellowstone, the hot springs and the geysers a government reservation, for the purpose of holding it forever as a national park. • Copies of the May and June numbers ot Scribner's Monthly. containing Langford's graphic story of "Tnc Wonders ol the Yellowstone," have been furnished to every member of Congress. Professor Hayden lias prepared an article f«r the February number of Scribner's. in which he confirms Langford's account. describes additional marvels discovd by himself, aud takes strong ground in favor of the park project. Such a park will, in time, attract to it crowds of the pleasure seekers and scientists of Europe It is not only remarkable for its scenery, but in a scientific point of view is said to be "the most marvelous region on the face of the earth." The illustrations, which are to appear in the February number of Scribtier, are lroin photographs taken by the recent expedition.</text>
    </result>
	    
    <result>
	    <id>/</id>
	    <rel>1</rel>
      <text>YELLOWSTONE ONE OF NATURE'S WONDERS Crowning Triumph of America's Wonderland. Yellowstone Park. WORDS FAIL TO DESCRIBE IT Ural of Scrlos of Illustrated Letters Devoted to the Curioui and Scautlful Sccnee la tlia Notlonal Reservation. Written for Tire Trllntne. Here boglns another chnpter of our Story. Having crnssed the continent over the main line of the Northern J'nelllo railway and witnessed. Its Rrnmli'tirvt scenery and Hiirnrlws for twentyftBht suifesHlve days, we will retrace our HtepH tor two thousand inlloa to LlvliiRston and Rather up Home of the wonderful scenery we lost In linssin";. We will re-enter for that purpose the portal of the Yellowstone National Park, "Tho Wonderland of North America." When this Indian reservation was set aside to be forever the Brand tourist reHort of the people and their common property by the peneral Kovernnient, few had any Idea of the endless variety and stupendous grandeur of the features embraced In tills tract of country Klxty-five by seventy-five miles In extent. This volcanic, region Is located about midway in our national domain. It nestles in the heart of the Kooky mountains covering un nrea of :i.57;i mpiure miles and Is encircled by ning liillcent snow peaks from ten to nearly fourteen thousand feet high. No valley within its limits has an elevation less than G.000 feet above sea level, while the averaK Is about H.UuO feet. This freak of nature is only a little spot of earth in the northwest coiner of Wyoming, coverliiff a few miles of Montana on the north and overlapping into Idaho and Montana on the west. It is one of thu preatPst water-sheds on the earth. Three of the larRest rivers in the United States have their source in Yellowstone park tho Missouri, the Yellowstone, the Snake. These Htrenims born within HlRlit of each other, lose themselves in three mighty rivers that seek old ocean thousands of miles apart from each other. Here, too, is the lar Reat body of water in North America lit this altitude of nearly 8,000 feet. Within this wonderful domain are fifty peysers which uro said to outclass MAMMOTH HOT nnythlnjj In the known world, throwing legulurly a column of hot water from thirty to two hundred and fifty feet in the air between intervals of from one minute to fourteen days, besides, within the boundaries of this wonderous geyser land there are known to be una hundred geysers and 3.600 springs and pools, together with paint pots, mud springs, lukes canyons, rivers and small parks, ad infinitum. Here in the "Grund Canyon of the Yellowstone," ten miles long with, an average depth of a quarter of a mile which 1 acknowledged to be the most brilliantly colored landscape in existence, and "Mammoth Hot Springs," the only colored terrace-building hot springs known that have such beauty and magnitude; also cliffs of volcanic glass, mountains of petrefactlon, hills or brimstone, unsurpassed waterfalls, interspersed with thousands of natural curiosities, surrounded by perpetual snow clad peaks which rise Into cloudland. all of which fittingly characterize this as the wonderland of America and of the world. ITS HISTORY AND DISCOVERY. This weird and enchanted spot Is only M recent .discovery. Often did the thought occur to us as w traversed it, why was it so long undiscovered. It was not until 1870 that this remarkable locality became known, although as far bark as 1806 some Inkling of what was to be found there was Riven by the Lewis and Clark exploring expedition. The stories then told came largely from frontier guides and mountaineers and were disbelieved, and more than Ixty years elapsed before the residents of Montana attempted to explore it, althought several expeditions sent out by the government had crossed the continent In search of the most suitable route for the Pacific railway; in fact, the whole western domain was crossed and re-crossed by these exploring parties, and still the Yellowstone Park country remained undiscovered. It was left to John Colter (the first white explorer) to know and tell of its wonders, and then to General Washburn, in 1870, to enter the inner wilds of this mysterious land, escorted by Lieutenant Doaae, of the United States army, and in 1871-72 for Professor P. T. Hayden, United States geologist, to make a thorough discovery under the sanction of congress and largely through his influence and efforts it became a national reservation. It peonis strange that a region so remarkable as this, was so long an unknown land to us. That, this is so. Is undoubtedly mvlng to the fact that from the east and south the Park is almost impossible of approach on account of the character of the mountains. The region is more than fifty miles south of the nearest route traveled by explorers, besides hostile Indians were in this immediate vicinity in very early days. But the question is aptly answered by Mr. O. D. Wheeler, probably the best informed of any of the Northern Pacific officials, who says in substance, "God moves in a mysterious way, and in His inscrutable wisdom He so concealed this grand heritage that it would not be discovered until the American people were sufficiently able to appreciate it, as to preserve it in all its integrity, its natural grandeur and beauty forever. Just as nature made it." Since the Park was reserved for its present purpose, congress has set aside as a "timber reserve" another tract on the south and east of about two thousand square miles, making the entire reservation one-fourth larger than my native state, Connecticut. This act prevents the timber here from being cut down or wantonly burdened under severe penalties. SPRINGS HOTEL. The completion of the Northern rarlfic railway across the continent was an important event for the Park, especially so when their branch line of fifty-one miles brought them to Cinna bar at its northern boundary. This road brings the tourist from his far away home and sets him down amidst the mountains and confines of this wonderland. "Thus far und no farther," said Mr. Wheeler to t ie, "Uncle Sam's edict to railroads, and none may venture beyond the imaginary boundary line." Connected with the Park are four Important factors, each Independent of the other, yet co-ordinate branches. These are the United States government, the Northern Pacific railway, the Yellowstone Pork association, and the Yellowstone National Park Transportation compuny. Like four separate, yet integral parts of the same machine, they work sympathetically and harmoniously toward the same end. The avenue of approach to the Park is one entirely in keeping with its character. Having given our readers a condensed outline of this mysterious land of wonders, we will invite them to follow us in our daily travels through it. We leave the main line of the road and start in to see the park at Livingston, for it's only through Livingston on the Northern Pacific road, that we can reach it. Livingston as described In a former letter, lies at the base of the Know and Helt ranges spurs of the Rocky mountains. Some people, like ourselves, have an idea, that we enter the Park on the same elevation above the sea, and in the same manner as it would enter Kaliniount Park, of Philadelphia, or Central Park, New York. This is a mistaken idea we commence at Livingston on elevation above sea level hi 4.4 .0 feet, and ascend to Cinnabar, fifty-one miles, on a grade of eighty feet to the mile overcoming 700 feet. We do not leave our drawing-room car until Cinnabar is reached. The ride through this interesting valley, bounded by mountains, is an appropriate prelude to what follows in the park itself. It is called a park. Your minds should be disabused of a misconception. It has nothing such as an ordinary park would indicate. No gravelled walks no velvety lawns, no statuary, no flower beds, etc., but all this extensive area is literally crowded with natural curiosities of the most wonderful character. The hotels and the government roads and bridges are the only artificial things to be found here, everything else being in its natural condition, rude, stern and wild. Three miles from Livingston, the railroad passes through the first "canyon of the Yellowstone," which forms a natural entrance into the Upper Yellowstone valley. This canyon is about a mile long and just wide enough to comfortably admit the road and river, the mountain walls rising 2,000 feet perpendicularly on either side. Passing through this first canyon we enter Paradise valley, which is from seven to twelve miles wide and extends some thirty miles along the Yellowstone river which tumbles and pounds continuously, clear as crystal and cold as ice. This valley has been settled by ranchmen. The land is very fertile and irrigation has been carried on to a high state of perfection, making the valley as productive as the corn belt of Illinois, The rich ranches stretching beyond the level upon the moraines, look like great Persian rugs with their harmonious blending of colors, but this is not the district in which one wishes to specify and particularize. As the train moves southward, the mountain scenery is ever changing and picturesque. The most prominent peak is Emigrant, in the south end of the valley, which rises proudly a mile and a quarter above the valley to an elevation of 11,629 feet. Forty miles from Livingston we pass through the "second canyon of the Yellowstone," called "Yankee Jim Canyon," named for an enterprising Yankee, who, prior to building the railroad, built a wagon road through the canyon at great expense and enjoyed a lucrative business in collecting toll from each visitor to the park. Yankee Jim is still located here and has many piscatorial guests during the tourist season, who find the best of trout fishing in these swift waters. This canyon is far more picturesque than the first, as the mountain walls rise higher, and the gorge within which the river is compressed is scarcely 100 feet wide. This valley is the bed of an ancient lake, with glaciated boulders strewn around, affording views of rocky cliffs and spurs. Cinnabar mountain is an object of interest. Here is a group of vertical beds nearly a half mile high. Extending from the base to the summit, is a reddish band of arenaceous clay about 100 feet wide, called Cinnabar, which gave the mountain its name. "The Devil's Slide" is found here, formed by two walls of trap-rock some 150 feet apart, which precipitates 2,000 feet down a mountain flank like a toboggan slide, and is strikingly realistic to the tourists. One says, "It demonstrates how easy His Satanic Majesty makes it in life for anyone to go down hill." STAGE TRANSPORTATION. Arriving at Cinnabar, the transportation company takes up the work of stage transportation through the park, a distance of one hundred and sixty miles. Here is a line of six-horse tally-ho coaches awaiting the tourist for a drive of seven miles to Mammoth Hot Springs hotel. Having exchanged our seats in the comfortable chair car for others equally inviting in the great coaches, we commence the ascent of 2,000 feet in seven miles to the famous hotel. This ride is the first day's pleasure drive in the park, and it is over an excellent macadamized road; and right here I wish to emphasize the superiority of TERRACES AT MAMMOTH SPRINGS. Yellowstone Park roads, for to me among the pleasant features of the park trip were the strong bridges, graceful curves and good roads. We wind along the Gardiner river, which has its source from the snow ravines of "Electric Peak," clear as crystal and cold as ice; this river unites with the Yellowstone at Cinnabar. The grade of the carriage road is very steep, as nearly 2,000 feet has to be overcome before reaching Mammoth Hot Springs, mainly in the last two miles, when the road leaves the river to ascend the mountain. Right at this point Boiling or Hot river empties into the cold, pure waters of the Gardiner. The former is the combined overflow of all the waters of Mammoth Hot Springs, made famous from the fact that fish may be caught in the cold stream and cooked in the hot stream without change of position. After a long climb a sudden turn is made, and the famous Mammoth Hot Springs hotel is seen in the distance, and presently we pass through a gateway of rock and behold the strangest and most fascinating sight unlike anything seen elsewhere, it is a range of snow-white terraces, rising like gigantic steps of marble forming a basin filled with boiling bubbling water, heated by nature's furnace, and sending forth clouds of steam. These terraces are gorgeously arrayed, exquisitely filigreed, and richly colored cliffs of "Mammoth Hot Springs." In front of us is a level plateau, where, besides the famous hotel, are several other buildings, among them Camp Sheridan, the headquarters of the superintendent of the park, and proudly floating from his official residence, was the "stars and stripes" which gracefully saluted us in acknowledgement of "three cheers for the old Flag," after we set foot on our own national domain, the wonderland of America. This park is under the exclusive control of the secretary of the Interior, with Contain George S. Hunter as superintendent, and two companies of cavalry. With United States soldiers for police, it is the most law abiding section in our country today. There are no saloons, no gambling houses, thieves, highway robbers, or Indian massacres. No man, except he be a federal officer, can carry fire-arms of any description. These two companies patrol the park that no act of vandalism be committed or the marvelous and delicate formations be disturbed. These soldiers stand guard over all this domain according equal rights to all and special favors to none. A st a' trout story and we close this, our first day's park experience. As we reached the "Boiling river" on our stage ride from Cinnabar, our attention was called to two gentlemen who were fishing in the ice cold Gardiner river. One of them had caught a trout and without unhooking it, he swung the line and fish over into the boiling river, and it was said the fish was cooked and ready for the table in less time than it takes me to tell the story. This is my first fish story. Tell me if this is not Wonderland. J. K. RICHMOND.</text>
    </result>
	    
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84027621/1904-12-24/ed-1/seq-8/</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn88084068/1916-06-22/ed-1/seq-3/</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn86075021/1888-07-04/ed-1/seq-2/</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn86075021/1889-06-27/ed-1/seq-4/</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84036008/1904-08-02/ed-1/seq-2/</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84036008/1909-07-13/ed-1/seq-2/</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn86075153/1914-12-17/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84036008/1905-09-22/ed-1/seq-8/</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>

    </results>
  </topic>
	
  <topic>
    <id></id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
	
  <topic>
    <id></id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>
